《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
24艘船跳跃走了
GAETA: Twenty-four ships jumped away.
几乎是三分之一的舰队了
That's almost a third of the fleet.
他们要追随罗丝琳去科波自取灭亡
TIGH: They're gonna follow Roslin to Kobol to their death.
凯莉开枪击中了莎伦
WOMAN: Cally shot Sharon!
有许多复制体  你还会再见到她的
ADAMA: There are many copies. You'll see her again.
其中的一个复制体向我父亲的胸部开了两枪
One of those things put two rounds into my father's chest.
我们已经发现了科波
ROSLIN: We have found Kobol.
当我们获得神箭之后将打开雅典娜之墓
And when we retrieve the Arrow, we will open the Tomb of Athena
我们将找到通往地球的道路
and we will find the road to Earth.
我想知道的就是
What I need to know
怎么找到雅典娜之墓
is exactly how to find the Tomb of Athena.
我可以为你指路
I can show you the path.
我不知道那条路有多长或是通向哪里
BOOMER: I don't know how long the path is, or exactly where it leads to,
但可以肯定的是你们要动作快
but I can tell you that you're gonna have to move very, very quickly.
立即把一切有关科波的侦察资料送到我房间里来
I want to see all recon material on Kobol immediately in my quarters.
科波
TIGH: Kobol?
我要让舰队重新凝聚到一起
I'm putting the fleet back together.
我要让我的家人重聚
I'm putting our family back together again.
经文上说我们中的一些人会死在科波上
The scriptures say some of us will die on Kobol.
比如阿波罗上尉？
Like a certain Capt. Apollo?
雅典娜之墓可能在任何地点
She could be anywhere.
如果仅靠帕蒂亚之书里的信息
If we only use information contained within the book of Pythia,
单从那段福音看来也符合总统的身份
which makes sense given the president's identification with that particular gospel,
那雅典娜之墓很有可能位于…
then the Tomb of Athena is most likely located somewhere
诸神之城以西山中的某个地方
in the mountains to the west of the City of the Gods.
我们假设她从最容易分辨的地标
Let's assume she starts at the most easily recognized landmark,
歌剧院开始
which is the opera house.
他们在这片草地周围休息过后...
ADAMA: They'd be setting down somewhere right here in this meadow,
将向西行进
then heading west.
您还好吧?
Are you okay?
恩
Yes. I am.
我们得从这沟壑出去
We got to get out of this ravine.
我可不想咱们被山洪冲走
I don't want us to get caught in a flash flood.
猛禽1号就在这地方的...
Raptor One went down
城市遗迹的外边坠毁的
right about here just outside the ruins of the city.
我们从没经过这里
Now we never made it past, say, here.
但我们目测侦察过进山的途径
But we visually scouted the approaches out to the mountains.
多谢
Thanks.
随时效劳
Any time.
如果就凭这些的话
If this is all she's got to go on,
我真不知道她想怎么找到这古墓
I don't know how the hell that woman thinks she's gonna find this tomb.
也许她曾在幻象中见到过
Well, maybe she's seen it in a vision.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
她说她看到了一些事物
She says she sees things.
图象  预言  还是什么的
Images, prophecies, whatever.
重要的是她相信这些事物 人们也因此支持她
The point is that she believes in them and so do the people that are with her.
长官  恕我直言 那里地势非常崎岖
Sir, with all due respect, that terrain is so rugged
不敢想象在没有地图或向导的情况下怎么通过那里
I can't imagine navigating it without a map or a guide.
好
Okay.
你是"山丘之王"
King of the hill.
"山丘之后"  非常感谢
Queen of the hill, thank you very much.
在风暴过去之前 我们应该躲起来
We should take shelter until the storm passes.
好主意  然后呢?
Sounds good. After that?
然后就开始最难的一个环节了
Then we start the tough part.
走吧
Let's go!
上一支救援队报告说 在科波附近没发现
The last rescue team reported no sign of a Cylon Baseship
任何基地飞船或突袭机的迹象
or a Raider anywhere near Kobol.
跳跃终点设置在高层大气外
We'll set the jump arrival coordinates in the upper atmosphere
以防万一
just in case.
长官  那很危险  以这艘船的大小也不可能
Sir, that's risky and it's certainly not possible with a ship of this size.
我乘一架猛禽号下去
I'll be going down in a Raptor.
什么?
What?
我不会让舰队没有防备
I'm not gonna leave the fleet undefended
我们大家一起去也太危险了
and it's too risky to try and take all of us.
干  我们可以派搜索队
Send a search party, for frak's sake.
"宙斯告戒12部落的首领...
"And Zeus warned the leaders of the 12 tribes
每个回到科波的人都会付出血的代价"
"that any return to Kobol would exact a price in blood. "
在我们身上是应验了
It certainly did for us.
不能再有流血事件了  损失已够惨重的了
No more bloodshed, enough loss.
我只带上完全必要的人
I'm only gonna take people who are absolutely necessary.
别和我争了  索尔
Don't try and argue with me, Saul.
事实是...
Truth is,
只有我才能与罗丝琳接触
I'm the only one that can reach out to Roslin.
反正一直都是我们俩之间的事
It's always been between us anyway.
我们可能去那里的时候是分开的 但我们会一起回来的
We may have gone down separately, but we're gonna come back together.
希望是站着回来
Hopefully on our feet.
但即使是在装尸袋里 我们也会一起回来
But even in body bags we're gonna be coming back together.
我要联系一下星际女皇
I'm gonna contact the Astral Queen.
看是否在天气放晴后可以把我们接走
See if they can pick us up until the weather clears.
这里不是你说了算  汤姆 一切通讯都要经我批准
You're not in charge here, Tom. All com traffic goes through me.
记住了
Try to remember that.
你还要等多久  汤姆?
How much longer do you want to wait, Tom?
你盯紧他们就是了
Just keep your eyes on him.
11点方向  仰角20度
BOOMER: 11:00. 20 degrees elevation.
山顶构成了一对双生岩
There's a formation of twin rocks up ahead.
恩  看到了
APOLLO: Yeah, I got it.
我想那是赫拉之门
I think those are the Gates of Hera.
你想?
You think?
我把经文以外的很多资料中的信息拼凑到一起
I'm putting together a lot of pieces from a lot of sources beyond your scriptures.
如果我说对了...
If I'm right,
据推测你们的神是站在那里
that's the spot where your god supposedly stood
看着雅典娜因为第13部落的人们大批离去...
and watched Athena throw herself down onto the rocks below
而绝望之下坠涧身亡的
out of despair over the exodus of the 13 tribes.
推测?
Supposedly?
赛昂人不是相信神吗?
I thought the Cylons believed in the gods.
恩  别让她开始说教了
STARBUCK: Yeah, don't get her started.
他们信仰的是一个真神或是什么的
They believe in one true God or something like that.
我们不会去膜拜假神
And we don't worship false idols.
你急忙地加入这个团队
You were quick enough to come on this mission.
带领我们来到了只有在我们的假经文中才提到的古墓
Lead us all to some tomb only actually mentioned in our false scriptures.
我们比你们更了解你们的宗教
We know about your religion than you do.
不管雅典娜是谁或是什么东西...
Athena's Tomb, whoever,
她的古墓很有可能就在那上面了
whatever she really was, is probably up there.
这倒是真的
That part is true.
总统女士  我们在夜幕降临之前赶不到那里
Madam President, we won't make it up there before nightfall.
走吧  看我们能走多远
Let's go, see how far we get.
这地方真让人郁闷
This is a depressing place.
我多少有些庆幸的是可怜的莎伦没来过这里
A part of me is glad Sharon never made it in here.
你想让这里添点光彩  是吧?
You decided to brighten up the place a little, did you?
我们的孩子将会在这里降生  在这房间里
Our child will be born here. In this room.
你没听我说话啊
You're not listening.
你注意到了?
Oh, you noticed?
我是没听  我受够了
No, I have had enough.
你一丝不挂地坐在那里
Do you seriously expect me to listen to you
怎么能让我专心听你说话?
while you sit around stark naked?
还唠叨我们之间这个虚构的孩子
Prattle on about this mythical baby of ours?
虚构的?
Mythical?
是的  虚构的
Yes, mythical.
你知不知道你现在变得有多不可理喻?
Do you have any notion of how ridiculous you've become?
我们的整个对话毫无逻辑可言
The whole turn of our conversation is completely shot to pieces.
我将成为我幻想中的女人所生的孩子的父亲
I'm the father of a baby who'll be born to me from my fantasy woman,
这个女人还只有我能看到
who I see solely in my head.
顺便说一句  我幻想中的女人已经不是我的幻想了
My fantasy woman, by the way, who stopped being my fantasy.
你再也不是我的幻想了
You're not my fantasy anymore.
可悲的是  你不过是一个卖弄风情的尘世女子而已
No, sadly now you're nothing more than a common tease.
我从没说过我会去生那孩子
I never said I would bear the child.
好极了  又是话里有话  玩心理游戏
Wonderful! More doubletalk. More mind games.
那好  那会是谁?
All right, then who is it gonna be?
谁会生下我们秘爱的孩子?
Who's going to bear our secret love child?
不是星芭儿  是吧?
It's not Starbuck, is it?
小心点  盖尤斯 你这么说话很危险
Careful, Gaius, you're in dangerous territory now.
我好怕怕
Then I guess I'm really scared.
这周又会发生什么大事件呢? 会是什么呢?
So, what's it going to be this week? What is it?
别告诉我  我来猜猜
Don't tell me, I'll guess.
船要爆炸了!
The ship's gonna blow up!
不对  见鬼
No, damn!
这人已经死了 那一定是其他人了
Done that one. So it's gotta be someone else.
是我?
Someone... Me!
对  当然是我啊!    我要爆炸了!好!
But, of course, me! I'm gonna explode! God!
神会让我人体自燃 然后变成个大火球
God is gonna make me spontaneously combust into a great big ball of flame,
然后卡拉狄加上的全体船员 手持"安宝莎"举杯庆祝
and then the whole crew of Galactica can celebrate on ambrosia.
一醉方休
Get really drunk.
好了  够了  我不能再这样下去了
Okay. Enough, I can't do this anymore.
你说得对  游戏结束  你赢了
You're right. Game's over you win.
我赢了?
I win?
我赢了什么?
What did I win?
你还不明白?
You don't get it?
拜托  盖尤斯  醒醒吧 想想精神方面的问题
Come on, Gaius, wake up and smell the psychosis already.
抱歉  我不明白你在说什么
I'm sorry, I don't know what you're talking about.
好  听我说
Okay. Look,
你的体内并没有被植入赛昂芯片
there's no Cylon chip implanted in your brain.
我不是真实的
I'm not real.
你并不是真的从赛昂人那里得到秘报
You're not really getting secret messages from the Cylons.
而是你疯了
You're just crazy.
很有意思
Very funny.
歇斯底里  你自己定夺的?
Hysterical. Do you write your own material?
你不相信我  是吗?
You don't believe me, do you?
对  不信
No, I don't.
有意思    我喜欢    是吧?
That's great! I love it. Is it?
好了  我受够了  知道吗?
Good. I've had enough of this, all right?
别再耍这套这鬼把戏了  好吗?
So can we just stop playing this stupid game?
对不起
I'm sorry.
但事实上  确实没有芯片这回事
But it's the truth. There is no chip.
如果没有芯片...
If there is no chip,
那你究竟是谁…
then who
是什么东西?
or what are you exactly?
我就是你
I'm you.
我是迷惑你心灵的潜意识
I'm your subconscious frakking with your mind.
好吧  是这样
Okay, check it out.
你帮助赛昂人对你的种族进行灭绝
You helped the Cylons commit genocide against your own people,
而你那脆弱的心灵承受不了这一切  所以...啪!
and your fragile little mind couldn't handle it. So, poof!
我的出现是要告诉你 你是多么特别
I appear and start telling you how special you are.
神是如何选择了你  得了
How God has chosen you. Yeah, right!
我不知道你现在又在耍什么把戏
Well, I don't know what game you're playing anymore.
可我不喜欢你那些愚蠢的花招  好了  你开心过了
But I'm not playing this stupid game, so, now you've had your fun.
你自己可以去做个身体检查
Why don't you get yourself checked out?
去医务室做个脑部扫描 这样就可以安心了  是吧?
Go down to sickbay and get a brain scan. That would settle it, wouldn't it?
去呀  你敢吗?
Go ahead. I dare you.
多简单啊
How simple could it be?
我们在北-西北的大陆
Okay, we're in the North-northwest continent.
C号象限仪的第2象限    也就是…
Quadrant C, Sector two, which...
干  让我看看能否判断方位
Oh, for frak's sake let me see if I can make heads or tails of it.
我尽力标出了地势形态  可我们…
Look, I marked the terrain as best I could, but we're not...
反正娘娘腔才去学地形学
Topography's for pansies anyways.
感觉如何?    外交官?
How're you feeling? Diplomatic?
我还是认为这么做不好  指挥官
I still don't think this is a very good idea, Commander.
我们最后一次见面的时候 她对我可不怎么高兴
The last time she saw me she wasn't too happy with me.
她信任你  重视你的意见  她会听你的建议的
She trusts you. Values your counsel. She'll listen to you.
我非常怀疑这点
I doubt that very much.
我是她的助理 我所说的话对她来说也
I'm her assistant. She doesn't put any more stock than what I say...
她认为你有朝一日会成为总统
She thinks you'll be president one day.
什么?
Excuse me?
她有一次对我这么说的
That's what she said to me once.
你让她想起了刚执政时候的阿达尔总统
That you reminded her of President Adar when he ran for his first office.
我不知道该怎么说了
I don't really know how to respond to that, sir.
别被这话冲昏了头脑  阿达尔是个白痴
Don't let it go to your head. Adar was a moron.
开始进入大气层
This is an intra-atmos entry.
你们系好安全带了吗?
You guys buckled in?
恩
ADAMA: Yeah.
封锁线周围安全 没有发现赛昂人
Perimeter's clear! No Cylon presence!
看到了吧?    没什么好担心的
See? Nothing to worry about.
我们已经开始走好运了
Having good luck already.
看到他和她在一起那样...让我背脊发凉
Gives me the creeps seeing him acting like that with her.
他爱她
He loves her.
他还知道她是一部机器
And, yeah, he knows she's a machine.
他不在乎这些  仍然爱她
He doesn't care. He loves her anyway.
干!我们的人怎么能被她们迷住呢?
Frak. How can one of us get that roped in by one of them?
我们也该留意点他
We should keep an eye on him, too.
西洛是我的朋友  知道吗?  他也是一个好人
Helo's a friend of mine, all right? He's one of the good guys.
是吗?
Yeah?
莎伦也曾是你的朋友
Sharon was a friend of yours, too.
感觉像是回到了卡布里卡
Feel like I'm back on Caprica.
不  谢谢了  我在这里很开心
No, thanks. I'm happy right here.
真的?
Really?
恩  真的  与你和卡拉在一起 我觉得自己像回家了一样
Yeah, actually. Just being with you and Kara feels like I've come home.
回到了舰队里
It's like I'm back in the fleet.
可你从没在舰队里呆过  那是另一个莎伦
But you were never in the fleet. That was the other Sharon.
恩  我知道
I know. I know that.
但这一切我全记得
But I remember all of it.
比如得到了我的飞行勋章  第一次在卡拉狄加上入港
Like getting my wings. My first trip aboard the Galactica.
身着制服的那段记忆太强烈  太真实了
You know, the memory of being in a uniform is so strong, so potent,
就像是我是莎伦·沃莱瑞  这里就是我的家
it's like, "I'm Sharon Valerii and this is my family. "
很怪异  是吧?
That's pretty weird, huh?
没关系
It's okay.
我喜欢怪人
I like weird.
失去了那个牧师真的让她惨兮兮的
Losing that priest really frakked her up.
她失去了很多人
She's lost a lot of people.
朋友  支持者
Friends, supporters.
只剩下她那年轻的王子了
All she has left is her young prince.
我们在这里  他也在这里
We're here. He's here.
我们都清楚该怎么做了吧
We know what we have to do.
这里的地形比我们想象的要险恶
Terrain's rougher than we thought.
还不知道要过多久才能到达古墓
Don't know how far until we reach this tomb.
你现在怎么退缩了?
Why are you backing out of this now?
我没有退缩
I'm not backing out of anything.
让双手沾满鲜血要比把血从手上洗掉难得多
Getting blood on your hands is a lot harder than washing it off.
那就让赛昂人来接手吧
Then let the Cylon do it.
如果是一个赛昂人拿了武器亲自杀了他呢?
What if the Cylon were to get a weapon and shoot him herself?
那样大家就会乱作一团 感到压力与恐慌
There'll be a lot of confusion, stress, panic.
那个赛昂人也会被轻易地除掉
Then the Cylon could find herself getting shot real easy.
你说这事怎么可能呢?
And how would you propose such a thing might happen?
必须要这样  汤姆  这你清楚
This has to happen, Tom. You know that.
找到古墓之后再说吧
Not until we find the tomb.
还有多长?
HELO: How much further?
"多远"
Farther.
什么?
HELO: What?
"多远"是用来描述确切距离的  "多长"是带有比喻色彩的
Farther describes actual distance, further is more figurative.
你现在成字典了?
What are you a dictionary now?
不好意思  我比你聪明
I'm sorry I'm smarter than you.
没关系  孩子有你的智商和我的长相就行
That's okay. The baby can have your brains as long as he gets my looks.
是吗?  那对她来说真是祝福了
Yeah, that'd be a real blessing for her.
她?
Her?
你知道是个女孩?
You know it's a girl?
恩
Yeah.
在我看来  赛昂人在卡布里卡有一个计划
STARBUCK: So from what I could tell, the Cylons have a plan for Caprica.
他们清扫尸体
They're cleaning up the bodies,
用重型机械来修理基础设施
bringing in the heavy machinery to fix the infrastructure.
我明白
I understand.
可他们并没杀光所有人
But they haven't killed everyone.
那里还有一支反抗军
There's a resistance movement.
一旦我们找到了古墓  拿到了地图
Once we find the tomb and get the map, I think our first order of business
我想我们首先要做的就是组织救援队返回卡布里卡
has to be planning a rescue mission back to Caprica.
中尉  我希望你知道你冒险为我所做的一切
Lieutenant, I hope you know how grateful I am for everything you've done
我是多么感激你  但现在我除了想找到古墓这件事
and what you risked, but right now I can't think about anything
别的什么都想不进去
but finding that tomb.
谢谢
Thank you.
舒服吗?    不能说话
Comfy? Can't talk.
不能动
Can't move.
那你...
Then you
肯定不想让我这么做
certainly wouldn't want me to do this.
我告诉过你别动
Oh, for... I told you not to move.
十分抱歉  医生  不会再出现这样的事了
I'm so terribly sorry, Doctor. It won't happen again.
好么  我还得重新设置 然后从头开始
All right. Now I have to reset and start from the beginning.
他还得重新设置 然后从头开始
Now he's got to reset and start all over again.
你为什么要这么对我?
Why are you doing this to me?
拜托  盖尤斯  在你发疯之前
Come on, Gaius, even back when you weren't nuts
你的脑袋里也是有一个细微的声音
there was always that little voice in your head.
那细微的声音帮你度过了艰难时期  记得吗?
That little voice helping you through the rough times, remember?
我只是那细微的声音的最新版本
I'm just the latest version of that little voice.
我一点也不相信你所说的话
I don't believe that for one moment.
不  神为我准备了一个计划
No, God has a plan for me.
"神的计划"?
God's plan?
恩  对  神是有个计划
Okay. Yeah, God has a plan and
神是存在的 那个神还对盖尤斯·波塔尔说话
there is a God and he talks to Gaius Baltar.
你给我闭嘴!
Okay. Shut up will you!
你别在那里发疯了  行吗?
Will you stop going crazy in there?
我没疯
I'm not crazy.
一旦你找到了古墓 你知道他会派人把你杀了  对吧?
Once you find this tomb, you know he's gonna have you killed, right?
他不是那种人
He's not like that.
他是士兵  你是敌人 这些是不会改变的事实
He's a soldier, you're the enemy. Nothing's gonna change that.
你的那个双胞胎  那个复制体
Your twin, your copy or whatever...
我知道
I know.
另一个莎伦开枪打了老头子 这我都听过上千遍了
The other Sharon shot the old man. I've heard it about a thousand times.
你记得开枪打他吗?
Do you remember shooting him?
不是我开的枪
It wasn't me.
你记得吗?
Do you remember?
不记得
No.
我知道了
I see.
那你认为她会有什么结果呢?
What do you think happened to her?
不知道
I don't know.
可能被关禁闭了或什么的
Probably threw her in the brig or something.
她被一个船员杀害了
She was murdered by one of the crew.
卡拉狄加上的人却都袖手旁观
And everyone aboard Galactica just let it happen.
你以为我说谎?  去问李吧
Think I'm lying? Ask Lee.
他们不会让你生下这孩子
They're not gonna let your child be born.
你以为他们能让你在他们眼皮底下  养育一个潜在的敌人?
You think they're gonna let you raise a potential enemy right in their midst?
如果你还想活着离开这个星球
You want to get off this planet alive,
就要小心你的自身安全了
you better start looking out for yourself.
嘘
Psst.
星芭儿
Starbuck.
希洛
Helo.
放下你的武器  上尉
Put down your weapon, Captain.
指挥官
Commander.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
总统女士
BILLY: Madam President.
比利
Billy.
比利  你可不知道...
Billy, you have no idea
有你在这里对我来说有多么重要
what it means to me to have you here.
我也很高兴见到您
It's good to see you, too.
我的天  指挥官
Oh, my gods. Commander!
她是自己人  指挥官
HELO: She's with us, Commander.
为什么?
Why?
指挥官!不!
ROSLIN: Commander, no!
离他远点儿!
Get off him.
我要你死
I want you to die.
指挥官   求你别这样  我们需要她
Commander, please don't. We need her.
指挥官  放开她吧
Commander, you got to let her go.
死
Die.
长官!
HELO: Sir!
爸?
Dad?
你说为什么会这样呢?
And you ask why.
没有  没有  还是什么都没有
Nothing, nothing, more nothing.
你满意了?
Are you satisfied?
是的  满意了
Yes. Yes, I am.
非常感谢  医生
Thank you very much, Doctor.
只是...
Just...
我们完全可以肯定了  是吧?  没有…
We're absolutely positive, aren't we, that there's no
不明物体?
unidentified objects?
利用你的个人时间 你想怎么看都可以
You can obsess over these as much as you like on your own time.
每艘船上都他妈的…
Freaking hypochondriac.
有个忧郁症患者
One on every bloody ship.
你干涉了一次军事行动
You interfered with a military mission
并且违背了你当初对我所做承诺
and you broke your word to me.
真正让你烦心的不是这事  对吧?
It's the second part that really bothers you, isn't it?
劳拉  我原谅你了
Laura, I forgive you.
谢谢你  比尔
Thank you, Bill.
我没求你原谅我
I didn't ask for your forgiveness.
反正你得到谅解了
Well, you have it anyway.
真不敢相信老头子有那样的反应
I can't believe the old man reacted like that.
他们杀了另一个莎伦
You know they killed the other Sharon?
什么?
What?
毫不留情地杀害了她 甚至都没有经过审讯
In cold blood, not even a trial.
你好
TYROL: Hi.
Hi.
莎伦?
Sharon?
你好  上士
Hello, Chief.
你认识我?
You know who I am?
恩
Yes.
我们没见过面  可是...
We haven't met but
我对你有印象
I remember you.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
那我们成什么了?
So where does this leave us?
回到了起点
Back to where we started.
还要受罗丝琳总统和阿达玛指挥官的奴役
Under the yoke of President Roslin and Commander Adama.
除非我们带着指明地球方位的地图回到船上
Not if we go back to the ship with a map to Earth.
然后编个许多人在科波上
And a sad story of how many people
惨遭赛昂人毒手的悲惨故事就行了
were killed down on Kobol by the Cylons.
结束了
It's over.
现在就罢手吧
Let it go for now.
瑟瑞丝中尉说殖民地上还有幸存者
Lieutenant Thrace says that there are survivors on the Colonies.
每天都有人反抗赛昂人
There are people fighting against the Cylons every day.
为了夺回他们的家园  他们的未来
They're fighting for their homes, their future.
我知道了
I see.
这难道没让你迟疑一下?
Doesn't give you pause?
也许在赛昂人袭击那天 你的那股冲劲是对的
Maybe your impulse the day the Cylons attacked was right.
也许我们本该留下来 捍卫我们的家园
Maybe we should've stayed and fought for our homes.
也许殖民地的总统
Maybe the President of the Colonies
本该和她的子民在一起
should've stayed with her people.
我不是为了这件事而来的
I didn't come here for this.
我来这里不是为了反思自身问题
I didn't come here to navel-gaze
或是归纳我们的错误
or to catalog our mistakes.
在遭受袭击之后 我们做出决定要离开殖民地
We made a decision to leave the Colonies after the attack.
我们做出的决定
We made that decision.
在那时是正确的决定 现在也是正确的
It was the right one then, it's the right one now.
因为在那以后的每时每刻...
So every moment of every day since then
都是一个礼物
is a gift.
神的礼物
From the gods?
不
No.
是你带给我们的礼物
From you.
说服我...应该离开那里
For convincing me that I should go.
否则我早就死了
I would be dead.
我儿子也会死
My son would be dead.
无论还有什么代价...
Whatever else the costs,
我都不会再去评判这个结果
I won't second-guess that outcome.
我看是时候该去寻找...
I think it's time to go find this
你所说的古墓了
tomb of yours.
凯莉杀了莎伦
So Cally kills Sharon
然后老头子就关她30天禁闭
and the old man gives her 30 days in the brig.
谋杀罪关30天禁闭
Thirty days for murder.
他们没把那看作是谋杀  西洛
They don't see it as murder, Helo.
我和你说的就是这事
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
你还是听不进去
That's what you're not hearing.
对他  对总统 对他们大家来说
To him, to the president, to all of them,
赛昂人不是人
Cylons aren't people.
我对他们来说不是人
I'm not a person to them,
而是一样东西
I'm a thing.
我不会坐视不管 让他们像杀害另一个莎伦一样加害你
I won't just stand by and let them kill you like the other Sharon.
知道吗?
Okay?
我相信你  西洛  真的
I believe you, Helo. I do.
但如果我们想拥有属于我们的未来...
But if we're gonna have any future together,
一切的一切...
any at all,
我就要亲自动手解决问题
I'm gonna have to take matters into my own hands.
什么意思?
What're you talking about?
你爱我吗?
Do you love me?
是的
Yes.
你信任我吗?
Do you trust me?
是的
Yes.
那就不要问我要去干什么
Then don't ask me what I have to do.
莎伦  你到底在说什
Sharon, what the frak are you...
相信我
Trust me.
相信我们
Trust us.
你考虑过我们之间的谈话了吗?
Have you had a chance to think about our conversation?
我一直在想这事
Haven't thought about anything else.
怎么样?
And?
等我们到了入口以后 他们就会放松警惕
When we get to the entrance, they'll be distracted.
我干掉父亲  你干掉儿子
I'll take the father and you take the son.
你们过来看看
You should see this!
瑟瑞丝中尉 我看你就顺便把它打开吧
Lieutenant Thrace, I hope you have that Arrow handy.
有些事你要知道
I need you to know something.
我是莎伦 但我是另一个莎伦
I'm Sharon but I'm a different Sharon.
我知道自己是谁
I know who I am.
我身上没有等待启动的隐含协议或程序
I don't have hidden protocols or programs lying in wait to be activated.
我自己做选择  自己做决定
I make my own choices. I make my own decisions
你要知道这是我自己的决定
and I need you to know that this is my choice.
一支老式斯塔林
This is one of the old stallions.
不是军用枪支
It's not military issue.
你到底从哪儿得来的?
Where the hell did you get this?
是他的
It's his.
慢点
Take it easy.
只是想...
Just wanted
看到你得偿所愿
to see you get your due.
你总是不听我的话
You never did listen to me.
这他妈的鬼东西就不能带一本操作指南?
Stupid frakking thing couldn't come with a handbook.
不可能  不然那样就太合情理了  是吧?
No, because that would just be too logical, wouldn't it?
"然后阿波罗之箭将打开雅典娜之墓"
"And the Arrow of Apollo will open the Tomb of Athena. "
恩  除非谁能找到钥匙孔或什么的
Yeah, well, unless anyone sees a keyhole, or whatever,
否则我们不是找错了地方
then we're either in the wrong place
就是完全被耍了
or we're just perfectly screwed.
我们还是...
ADAMA: Okay, then why don't we just...
西洛  过来
Helo, come here.
数到三 一  二  三
APOLLO: On three. One, two, three!
动了
There it is.
天那
Oh, my gods.
你先请吧
After you.
西洛  你留在外面      是  长官
Helo, you stay out. Yes, sir.
上士    长官?
Chief? TYROL: Sir.
留守大家
ADAMA: Guard everybody.
是  长官
TYROL: Yes, sir.
如果没用神箭就打开了这座古墓
STARBUCK: If the Arrow didn't actually open the tomb,
我们怎么能确定就是这里呢?
how do we know this is the right place?
不能确定
We don't.
但这确实是座古墓
But it's a tomb all right.
经文上说需要神箭才能找到地图
The scriptures say you need the Arrow to find the map.
这些破碎的雕像  我认识
These broken statues, I recognize them.
公羊  爱诺朗
The ram, Aerilon.
杰米朗  双胞胎
Gemenon, the twins.
这些是12部落  12殖民地的雕像
These are the icons of the 12 tribes, the 12 Colonies.
这里才是一切开始的地方
This is really where it all began.
我们都是从这个地方而来的
STARBUCK: We all came from this place.
这个可能是派亢  一条鱼
This could be Picon, the fish.
我猜这位年轻的女士应该是沃钢吧?
I guess, this little lady could be Virgon, right?
山羊就代表卡布里卡
The goat, Caprica.
撒纪特恩
ROSLIN: Sagittaron,
弓箭手
the archer.
他缺了什么东西
He's missing something.
我们到底在哪里?
APOLLO: Where the hell are we?
不知道
ROSLIN: I don't know.
我想是雅典娜之墓吧
Tomb of Athena, I think.
我们不是已经进到古墓里了吗
I thought we were already in the tomb.
我想那只是大厅吧
STARBUCK:I think that was the lobby.
又是这些古代符号
Again the ancient symbols.
这些图案...
ROSLIN: These patterns
是12殖民地还采用古名的时候
were on the original flags of the 12 Colonies,
每个殖民地旗子上早先的符号
back in the days when the Colonies were called by their ancient names:
白羊座
ROSLIN: Aries.
金牛座
Taurus.
双子座
Gemini.
巨蟹座
Cancer.
狮子座
Leo.
天秤座
ROSLIN: Libra.
处女座
Virgo.
那些宝石与星座相对应
ADAMA: The jewels match the constellations.
这就是地图
APOLLO: This is the map.
到达地球的地图
This is the map to Earth.
也许吧
ADAMA: Maybe.
那地球就在其中一个星座的里面吗?
So is Earth in one of these constellations?
我们正站在它上面
We're standing on it.
我们正站在地球上
We're standing on Earth.
经文上说...
STARBUCK: The scriptures say
当第13个部落降落到地球上以后...
that when the 13th tribe landed on Earth,
他们仰望星空看到了他们的12个兄弟
they looked up into the heavens and they saw their 12 brothers.
在地球上...
ROSLIN: Earth is the place
你可以仰望苍穹
where you can look up in the sky
看到12殖民地所在的星座
and see the constellations of the 12 Colonies.
可我还是不知道这对我们来说有什么用
I don't know what good it's gonna do us though.
我们该怎么做?
Then what are we supposed to do?
在整个银河里搜寻一个行星图案?
Search the entire galaxy for one particular star pattern?
那里  在天蝎座里  我以前见过
There. There in Scorpio. I've seen that before.
是礁湖星云
APOLLO: It's the Lagoon nebula.
M8星云
ADAMA: Astro body M8.
离这里好远啊
That's a long way from here.
恩
Yeah.
可至少我们现在有了...
But at least now we have
地图和方向
a map and a direction.
从遭受袭击那天开始  我们就努力抗争
We have struggled since the attacks,
相互依靠
trying to rely on one another.
作为每个人  我们的力量和唯一的希望...
Our strength, and our only hope as a people
就是要做到团结一致  永不分离
is to remain undivided.
我们并未尽全力保证这点
We haven't always done all we could to ensure that.
许多人相信经文...
Many people believe that the scriptures,
神的书信...
the letters from the gods,
将会拯救我们
will lead us to salvation.
也许确实如此
Maybe they will.
但"天助互助者"
"But the gods shall lift those who lift each other. "
因此  为了救助我们大家
And so, to lift all of us,
让我再次为各位请出...
let me present once again
殖民地的总统  劳拉·罗丝琳
the President of the Colonies, Laura Roslin.
谢谢
Thank you.
我没事
I'm okay.
真的  挺好的
I'm okay, really.
恩
Yeah?
只是...
It's just...
我不想让我们的孩子生在这牢房里
I don't want our baby born in this cell.
那孩子?
Their child?
我告诉过你一个孩子将会降临
I told you a child would arrive.
告诉过你她会在这房间里出生
Told you it would be born right here in this room.
你怎么能怀疑我所说的话呢?
How could you ever doubt me?
布玛儿将会生下...
Boomer is going to bear
我们的孩子?
our child?
那是她本不应得到的荣誉
An honor for which she is hardly deserving,
但我不会对神的旨意提出质疑
but one doesn't question God's will.
你不是一块芯片
Well, you're not a chip.
这我们已经确定了
That we've established.
对
Yes.
但莎伦的怀孕证明你并非
BALTAR: Sharon being pregnant does suggest
是我的潜意识在作祟那么简单
that you are rather more than a simple manifestation of my subconscious.
我没有...
I'm not...
疯?    对
Crazy? No.
那你...
Then who,
究竟...
or what,
是谁...
are you
是什么东西?
exactly?
我是被派来保护你的神的天使
I'm an angel of God sent here to protect you.
来指引你  来爱你
To guide you, to love you.
要到什么时候?
To what end?
人类的末日
To the end of the human race.